[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：所以布尔值，在这种语言中正好有两个布尔值
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So Booleans, there are exactly two Booleans in this language and
它们是真的，也是假的。
they are true and false.
所以万岁，我们做对了。
So hooray, we got that right.
我们有条件。
We have strings.
有人知道为什么叫弦吗？
Does anybody know why they're called strings?
任何人？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：字符的更改。
Anyone? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: The change of characters.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：原来没有人
&gt;&gt; Douglas: It turns out nobody
知道。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
knows. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：我第一次去的地方
&gt;&gt; Douglas: The first place I've been able
为了在引用特定数据类型的文献中找到，
to find in the literature that refers to a specific data type,
这是一个字符序列，是ALGOL 60报告。
which is a sequence of characters, is the ALGOL 60 report.
但那份报告中没有解释他们为什么选择字符串这个词。
But there's nothing in that report which explains why they chose the word string.
当你第一次遇到它的时候，你一定会想，
The first time you encountered it you must have thought,
这很奇怪，因为它看起来不像一根绳子。
well this is strange cuz it doesn't look like a piece of string any way.
那是怎么回事？
So how'd that happen?
我问了那个委员会的约翰·麦卡锡
I asked John McCarthy who was on that committee,
他是Lisp的发明者，为什么他称它为字符串？
he was the inventor of Lisp, why did he call it strings?
他说，好吧，Clanet是用一串符号来做这件事的。
He said, well Clanet was doing this stuff with strings of symbols.
但这并没有真正回答问题，因为在Algol 60的时候
But that didn't really answer the question because at the time of the ALGOL 60
报道说他们会谈论一块是一连串的声明。
report they would talk about a block was a string of statements.
那么，它什么时候变成了具体的字符串呢？
So when did it become specifically a string of characters?
我问了一个他不知道的问题，他真的很生气
And he was really annoyed that I was asking a question he didn't know
答案是。
the answer to.
所以这就是那次谈话的结束，然后他死了，
So that was the end of that conversation and then he died and
他是Lisp委员会最后的幸存者
he was a last survivor of that of the Lisp committee so
我们永远不会知道，也不会知道Algol委员会。
we'll never know, or of the ALGOL committee.
所以不管怎样，我们得到了它们，我们称它们为字符串
So anyway we got them, we call them strings and
我认为我们称它们为字符串是因为可能存在一些CPU架构
I think we call them strings because there may have been some CPU architecture
其将字符链接在一起以形成字符的字符串序列。
which linked characters together to make string sequences of characters.
我认为这是因为我们对弦的操作是什么？
And I think that because what's the operation we do on strings?
它是连接，但是连接意味着形成链接，
It's concatenate, but concatenate means to form links,
这是链条制造中的一种操作。
it's an operation in chain making.
所以你会认为，如果是弦，它应该是领带，或者是切片，或者是风，或者
So you would think if it's strings it should be tie or maybe slice or wind or
弦做的事情。
something that strings do.
所以我们有一些混合的隐喻在进行。
So we've got some mixed metaphors going on.
所以我仍然在搜索文献，试图找出字符串的来源
And so I'm still searching the literature trying to find out where strings came from
但我还没找到。
but I haven't found it yet.
所以不管怎样，我们有了他们，我们有了条件。
So anyway we got them, we got strings.
字符串是0位或更多16位Unicode字符的序列。
A string is a sequence of 0 or more 16-bit Unicode characters.
它的字符是UCS-2意义上的，而不是UTF-16意义上的
It's characters in the sense of UCS-2 not UTF-16
因为没有代理项对的意识。
because there's no awareness of surrogate pairs.
在JavaScript和
At the time that JavaScript and
Java被设计成Unicode将是一个16位字符集。
Java were designed Unicode was gonna be a 16 bit character set.
后来它增长到了21位字符集，而JavaScript并没有意识到这一点。
It later grew to a 21 bit character set and JavaScript is not aware of that.
没有单独的字符类型。
There is no separate character type.
字符表示为长度为1的字符串。
Characters are represented as strings with a length of one.
字符串是不变的，这是好的。
Strings are immutable which is good.
一旦你做了一个字符串，它就不能改变了，它一直都是固定的。
Once you make a string, it cannot be changed, it's fixed for all time.
您可以通过将旧字符串的比特连接在一起来生成新字符串，但是
You can make new strings by concatenating together bits of old strings but
一旦制作好字符串，您就不能更改它。
you cannot change a string once it's made.
相似的字符串是相等的，这是伟大的。
Similar strings are equal which is great.
Java做错了，JavaScript做对了，JavaScript万岁。
Java got that wrong, JavaScript got that right, hooray for JavaScript.
字符串文字可以与换位一起使用单引号或双引号。
String literals can use single quotes or double quotes with escapement.
两者的工作方式完全相同。
Both work exactly the same way.
没有魔术引号或准引号或类似的东西。
No magic quotes or quasi quotes or anything like that.
但是没有理由有两种方法来制作弦，但是我们做了。
But there's no reason to have two ways to make strings but we do.
因此，我建议对外部字符串使用双引号。
So given that I recommend use double quote for external strings.
在程序之外有意义的字符串，如URL和
Strings that make sense outside of the program like URLs and
模板和给用户的注释，诸如此类的东西。
templates and notes to the user, that kind of stuff.
并对内部字符串使用单引号，如属性名称和
And use single quotes for internal strings like the names of properties and
字符常量之类的东西。
character constants and stuff like that.
没有什么可以强制执行这一点，但我认为这是一个很好的惯例。
There's nothing that enforces that but I think it's a good convention.
我们可以使用数字的toString方法将数字转换为字符串。
We can convert a number to a string by using its toString method.
相反，我更喜欢使用全局字符串函数，它做同样的事情，并且
I prefer instead to use the global String function which does the same thing, and
也会在没有toString方法的事情上更好地工作。
will also work better on things that do not have toString methods.
我们可以使用全局数字函数或将字符串转换为数字
We can convert a string into a number by using the global Number function or
通过使用我更喜欢的加号前缀运算符。
by using the plus prefix operator which I prefer.
我们还有一个我不喜欢的parseInt函数。
We also have a parseInt function that I don't like.
parseInt是从Java借用的东西。
parseInt is something that was borrowed from Java.
它会将一个值转换成一个数字，但是
It will convert a value into a number but
它在第一个非数字字符处停止解析。
it stops parsing at the first non-digit character.
它不会告诉你它停在哪里，为什么停下来，或者留下了什么。
And it won't tell you where it stopped, or why it stopped, or what was left over.
通常想知道这一点，因为这可能很重要，但是
And usually wanna know that cuz that can be important but
它不会给你任何线索。
it doesn't give you any clue.
存在一个很大的设计错误，因为如果要解析的字符串以
There was a big design error in that if the string you are parsing starts with
0，它假设您的意思是将其解析为基数为8的八进制。
a 0, it assumes that you meant that to be parsed as base-8, octal.
因此，如果您正在解析诸如日期或时间之类的内容，则可能会有一个08或
And so if you're parsing something like a date or a time which might have an 08 or
09将被解析为0，因为它看到0，进入基数8，
an 09 that will be parsed as a 0 because it sees the 0, goes into base-8,
它看到8，说你不是一个八进制数字，所以我在这里停下来，得到0。
it sees the 8, says you are not an octal digit so I stop here and get the 0.
是的，正因为如此，我建议你总是包括基数论点，
Yeah, so because of that I recommend you always include the radix argument,
上面写着基数是10。
which says base-10.
我们在地球上，该死的，我们有10基数，
We're on planet Earth, damn it, we got base-10,
0到9。&gt；&gt；Douglas：字符串
0 to 9. &gt;&gt; Douglas: Strings
有一个length属性，它告诉您字符串中有多少个16位字符。
have a length property which tells you how many 16-bit characters are in the string.
代理项对将被计为该计数中的两个字符。
Surrogate pairs will be counted as two characters in that count.
字符串是对象，因此它们包含一大堆方法，
Strings are objects and so they contain a big mess of methods,
让你离线查找它们，但是它们很多。
let you look them up offline, but there are a lot of them.
他们中的许多人实际上是非常有用的。
Many of them are actually very useful.
每个字符串都继承自string.prototype。
Every string inherits from string.prototype.
所以如果我们想要添加新的
So if we wanted to add new
方法到字符串，这是我们可以做到这一点的地方。
methods to strings this is the place where we could do that.
同样，这不是应用程序可以做的事情，但是
Again, this is not something applications can do but
这就是我们一直在发展语言的方式。
this is how we've been growing the language.